Guide to the Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Sciences Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Sciences records
1953-1954
SC0856
Stanford University
1.75 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Biographical/Historical note
The Ford Foundation funded surveys of the behavioral sciences at several universities in the early 1950s with the aim of extending and improving research facilities. The topics the surveys investigated included academic and administrative structures, student population, existing research programs, curriculum, and personnel.
Scope and Contents note
Collection includes Stanford's proposal to the Ford Foundation; typescript reports by academic departments and programs, the library, Hoover Institution, the Food Research Institute, and various committees; assorted memos, agenda, and correspondence; the final Report of the Executive Committee and Staff, issued in July 1954; and W. Allen Wallis's report THE 1953-54 PROGRAM OF UNIVERSITY SURVEYS OF THE BEHAVIORAL SCIENCES, April 1955.
Access Terms
Ford Foundation; Wallis, W. Allen, (Wilson Allen), 1912-; Social sciences--Research.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Stanford’s proposal to the Ford Foundation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation Program of University Surveys of the Behavioral Sciences. Report of the Visiting Committee, Chicago, Oct. 1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assorted memos, notices, agenda, and correspondence 1953-54 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - International Relations and Area Studies (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economics Department (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Far Eastern Studies (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Food Research Institute (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Geography (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hispanic American Studies (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - History Department (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hoover Institution and Library (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Institute for Journalistic Studies (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - International Relations Program (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - University Libraries (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Political Science (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Psychology (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Special Committee on Research Programs (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Sociology and Anthropology (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Curricula (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Draft report outlines (2 versions) (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Report of the Visiting Committee on the Survey at Stanford, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Behavioral Science Survey Documents Volume 1 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Behavioral Science Survey Documents Volume 2 1954 [contents are a duplicate of volume 1] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Draft report of the Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Sciences (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notes found in copy of the final report (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Science 1953-1954. Report of the Executive Committee and Staff July 1954. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Science 1953-1954. Report of the Executive Committee and Staff July 1954. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Draft Report. Temporary Advisory Committee of the Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Sciences. 1953 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Stanford Survey of the Behavioral Science. Report of the Visiting Committee, September 1954. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wallis, W. Allen. The 1953-54 Program of University Surveys of the Behavioral Sciences. Behavioral Sciences Program, The Ford Foundation. February 22, 1955 [draft] (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Wallis, W. Allen. The 1953-54 Program of University Surveys of the Behavioral Sciences. Behavioral Sciences Program, The Ford Foundation. April 18, 1955. (Box 4, Folder 4)